# Geyslan Gregório Bem

Juazeiro do Norte, Brazil geyslan@gmail.com Phone: 55 88 9617 0441 Postal Code: 63034-100

## Summary

Graduating in computer science having expertise in software development, great professional relationship and focused at work. With more than 10 years of experience in development and 3 using basically C and Assembly languages and Linux platform. Looking now for new challenges and opportunities that allow him to learn new technologies and work with new people. With great interest in software development (Assembly, C/C++, Python, Ruby, ShellScript, Lisp), mainly in linux kernel development.

Open Source developer contributing in projects like: Linux, OSv, Metasploit, radix, SLAE, uzumaki, C in Fork Book etc.

By 2013 began studying the Linux Kernel by code analysis. Contributed effectively in patching several bugs as well as improving its code.

Recently (2014), started to contribute with the OSv Kernel as well.

### Education

Universidade Estácio de Sá, Graduating in Computer Science.

### Experience

## Open Source Developer

Jan 2013 - Present

Random hacking

Kernel hacking: Linux and OSv;

Studying over OSDev and kernel internals that lead him to contribute sending patches to Linux Kernel and after to the new OSv kernel for clouds.

## Tribunal Regional do Trabalho da 7ª Região

Oct 2012 - Present

Judiciary Technician

Government Employee: Director's Assistant;

Analysis of court cases and decisions that depends on the responsibility of how to know to enforce the federal law. And maintenance on computer equipment, as a sport.

### Bradesco Bank

Jan 2007 - Jul 2012

Executive Commercial Manager

Bank Executive;

Coordinated 72 bank agencies. Besides the formal banking attributions, developed excel sheets (VBA macros) to automatically track the diary agencies results by email. Before assuming that role, was Administrative Manager in two agencies and Administrative Supervisor.

## Diretorium Informática

Set 2008 - Dec 2011

 $Software\ Engineer$ 

Main Technologies: Delphi, Object Pascal, C, Paradox, Firebird, DBMS;

Member of a team responsible to design and develop three commercial systems:

- \* Developed SALE (Sistema de Acompanhamento de Logística e Estoque), a software program for control logistics and product stock. The SALE runs in Windows platform and was developed using Delphi with Firebird.
- \* Help improve and correct bugs in SEV (Sistema de Estoque e Vendas), a software program for stock and sales control. Runs in Windows and was developed using Delphi with Paradox.

\* Improvement of Lockar, a movie rent system that runs in Windows. Lockar was developed using Delphi with Paradox. It initiated as commercial software but after was deployed as freeware.

Other activities involved: Operating system and network administration, Delphi and C development, debugging, profiling, code analysis etc.

#### Skills Base

Operating System: Linux (Debian, Ubuntu, Arch Linux), Windows NT/XP/Vista/7;

Networkings: TCP/IP protocol suite;

*Progamming Languages*: C/C++, Pascal, Python, ShellScript, eLisp, plus some experience in Ruby;

Virtualization: VirtualBox and qemu;

Languages: Fluent in Portuguese, Intermediate in English and Elementary in Japanese (Phonetic Syllabaries);

# Open Source Projects

• SLAE: Security Linux Assembly Expert course assignments. All seven assignments accomplished with merit. This project resulted in the creation of some of the smaller shellcodes of its kind in the world. Smaller than those present in Metasploit. Eg. Tiny Shell Bind TCP and Shell Bind TCP Random Port (latter is unique of its kind).

(https://github.com/geyslan/SLAE)

- radix: A kernel project for academic purposes that uses grub and its multiboot support. It is maintened by radix-kernel organization.

  (https://github.com/radix-kernel/radix)
- uzumaki: A simple Emacs buffers cycler that optimize the swapping between open buffers in that famous editor.

  (https://github.com/geyslan/uzumaki)
- C in Fork Book: It is a pilot project to write a book about the C programming language addressing beginners in computers. It will be originally written in Portuguese but with plans to be translated into English.

  (https://github.com/c0defellas/c.in.fork.book)

### More Info

- Linkedin: http://www.linkedin.com/in/geyslan
- Github: https://github.com/geyslan
- Personal page: http://www.hackingbits.com